<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on randy chang</title>
    <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on randy chang</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 13:36:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 13:36:11 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, and this is &lt;em&gt;emphasized&lt;/em&gt; text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&#34;randyxchang.com&#34;&gt;old randy&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt; website!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/05-2324-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/05-2324-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;23:27&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have spent nearly two hours trying to find a reasonable flight to Anchorage. I was willing to fly from four different airports. The one reasonable flight (reasonable = wouldn&amp;rsquo;t require me give up two+ days in Asia/cost below $3000 for a one way/require four total days of travel) was on a website called Ovigo. After filling out all my information, and clicking book, the website simply did not process a booking (I even called Amex to check).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/1.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a few kinds of in between; semester one&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nulla&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel very clear on things. My speculation is that, as life goes on, certain doors close, and the light that filtered out of them no longer confuses, say, someone staring down a long stretch of hallway, in a way that almost guarantees clarity. Labels like &amp;ldquo;parent&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;whatever future career&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; are nice handrails that are also very much defined by what they are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. open as opposed to their closed counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/2.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/2.5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;from january to march&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Noah texted me today that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t written all of 2025. I told him I was ~500 words from finishing a [[on agency, the dark arts, and paperclips|gargantuan post]] that encompassed my time in Taiwan, the Middle East, and interviewing a local union organiser. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Yet I doubt those 500 words will arrive anytime soon, and so here are the small things I&amp;rsquo;d like to tell you about in between, amounting to roughly 500 words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things a teacher said to me that changed my life, at least the way I understood it, was that &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s a delicate balance between showing vulnerability and imposition&amp;rdquo;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In that spirit, year reflections are a tricky piece of writing. Here&amp;rsquo;s, I suppose, my self-perception of where I&amp;rsquo;m at now, and how that&amp;rsquo;s changed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;as-of-now&#34;&gt;as of now&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nearer to &lt;em&gt;the start&lt;/em&gt; section of this year, Jordan Guilford stopped me before I was about to start my workout. Trembling, I thought I was in trouble for not moving enough weight or working out inefficiently or something. Instead, he asked me how in touch with my soul I felt. I had never been asked a question remotely close to that. My soul was now the one shaken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I possess what I think I can call &amp;ldquo;reasonable impatience.&amp;rdquo; I read really fast, mainly because I have a habit of skipping description.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a symptom of a larger problem, which I will call the optimisation issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know roughly what a home looks like — chairs, tables, walls, roof — and knowing that the ottoman is beige and historically significant doesn&amp;rsquo;t add meaningfully to understanding that the antique dealer character probably has good taste in furniture. Again, forgive the snarky, dramatic turn of phrase.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/baby-baby-crab-rangoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/baby-baby-crab-rangoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;short&#34;&gt;short&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title is totally unrelated to content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;medium&#34;&gt;medium&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was walking down Euclid Ave. around seven (am). I saw a guy wearing a shirt with this on the back. It made me happy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;long&#34;&gt;long&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What hasn&amp;rsquo;t been making me happy (at least not exactly) recently? My espresso machine. This thing man.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s probably something deeply romantic and aesthetic about making your coffee in a ritualistic, perfected routine. You wake up, you stand in front of this metal contraption. You shake out some beans from a local roaster that probably makes coffee ~twelve times better than your Reddit-powered charlatan &amp;ldquo;expertise&amp;rdquo;, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, because you&amp;rsquo;ve learned words like &amp;ldquo;portafilter&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;crema&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;extraction&amp;rdquo;; you vaguely know the difference between a conical burr and a flat burr; you&amp;rsquo;ve shed a small tear at how expensive a &amp;ldquo;setup&amp;rdquo; is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/chill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/chill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;going out in &amp;amp; of Chapel Hill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent &amp;ldquo;fall break&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with Lawrence and Dua — two recurring characters — outside of Chapel Hill. My dorm became the occasional pit stop rather than a place to sleep; one advisor&amp;rsquo;s home &amp;amp; one friend&amp;rsquo;s home hosted evening festivities; our adventures spanned Durham, Charlottesville, and Minecraft seed 8584926385964346659.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Over the afternoon coffees that seem to conclude every friend group meetup — putting a bow on four Cookout runs, two draft Instagram posts, and a round of TopGolf — we discussed our next destinations: considering Abu Dhabi, Taiwan, Japan, finalising with the painful realisation I was no longer nomadic, and that such travel is now both irresponsible and inconvenient.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/chipotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/chipotle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;the irie jamaican kitchen pamphlet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;i. I saw Hamilton a few days ago. In honour of that:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An impromptu bingo game at the consignment store for school supplies we were meant to visit meant our presence was no longer possible. We instead took the crosswalk necessary to a bare-bones boxing gym, which had turned into an off-season football camp for a team, none of whom were above the age of twelve. I was familiar with the &amp;ldquo;how many twelve year olds could you beat in a fight&amp;rdquo; question, but I realised my answer to &amp;ldquo;how many twelve year olds could you beat in a pushup contest&amp;rdquo; was much less, numerically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/houston/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading &lt;em&gt;The Woman Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, which appeals using elements similar to Shang-Chi &amp;amp; teaches using elements very dissimilar to Shang-Chi. Over the last week, I&amp;rsquo;ve read pages and pages of stuff that is, in some way, tangentially related to being Asian-American&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  The only line I can remember came in this one: &amp;ldquo;In America my mother has eyes as strong as boulders.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think I have soft eyes. I trust easy &amp;amp; laugh often; I truthfully cannot believe how fortunate my life has been. My parents&amp;rsquo; eyes have softened over time, I&amp;rsquo;ve found, and I&amp;rsquo;m primarily fortunate because I got to skip to that stage, I think. Re Amy Chua, it&amp;rsquo;s possible my kids&amp;rsquo; eyes will be mush.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/material-pleasures-and-the-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/material-pleasures-and-the-classics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my English teachers — although I guess we call them professors now — is a bearded, whipsmart, older man. He is, in both physical appearance and mental sharpness, comparable to the other two fantastic English teachers I&amp;rsquo;ve had: one that taught me for seven hundred days, the other for seven.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I write this as I am simultaneously meant to be writing a &amp;ldquo;COVID narrative&amp;rdquo; for his class.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite quotes I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard is from one extremely wealthy guy I know giving advice to a newly minted wealthy guy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/on-agency-the-dark-arts-and-paperclips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/on-agency-the-dark-arts-and-paperclips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;taipei and toronto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the writing on this website is &lt;del&gt;intentionally&lt;/del&gt; unreadable. I enjoy the exercise of compressing and uncompressing, like putting the same sentence through Google Translate forty times. This post was meant to be about how I think now; what&amp;rsquo;s changed; and how I feel. However, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to answer all these questions. In exchange, inspired by recent (e)motions,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; here&amp;rsquo;s a semi-readable writeup two (plus six) weeks later; four (plus six) flights later; an intended 500 (plus and additional 1000) words later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/on-arrogance-quality-aesthetics-and-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/on-arrogance-quality-aesthetics-and-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about four things lately. Here they are, and where I stand on them as of now (opinions that might change even a hour from now, let alone looking back in the further future). Published October 2nd, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is blogging arrogant? At its core, a personal blog is sharing writing about your own life for the consumption of others, or about sharing your own opinions on various subjects. Most blogs are also rife with little idiosyncrasies, design quirks, and writing styles that are simultaneously personal and meant to impress onto a reader more of your personality. These both require the natural assumption that your reader is interested — interested in your design quirks, in your opinions, in your life — which may be a trait that arrogance shares. I&amp;rsquo;m not arguing all bloggers are egotistical. Though I do think if done incorrectly, this act of throwing writing out into the world can be &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; — which is funny, because throwing writing out into the world can also be a deeply humbling experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On quality. I don&amp;rsquo;t think my writing is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;. Simple as that. I rarely edit before posting and I don&amp;rsquo;t spend huge amounts of time planning. Instead, when I want to write out my thoughts on something, I write, and then I post. I wonder if I stop posting so much, and instead take time — time to digest an experience, a book, etc — I might produce better writing. The original philosophy of this website was almost about leaving an online record for myself down the line, but it might be arrogant (see above) to assume that non-edited, raw writing deserves to be public-facing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This whole idea of &amp;ldquo;beauty is terror&amp;rdquo; has been echoing in my mind, because I keep recognising there are lots of aesthetically beautiful things around me, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t read any other philosophical explanation of aesthetic beauty, meaning this theory of &amp;ldquo;beauty is terror&amp;rdquo; just keeps getting prompted whenever I see something pretty. I recently went to the cathedral light show in Reims, whose beauty absolutely shut my friend and I up (we are normally a very rambunctious duo; we never seem to stop speaking or laughing loudly, which I am sure is not aligned with French — or global — politesse). One could say we were awed into silence. Or terrorised. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s up to philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The future. I wrote, indirectly, some of my thoughts on this in the [[novelist as a vocation]] post. Basically, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about how to live as much as possible (not in quantity of years, but in amount of novel experiences). One approach that a lot of the blog writers I like do, is to do cool things in some self-imposed, borderline ascetic manner. The most personal development I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten (see [[the catcher in the rye]]) was also done in this manner, indirectly. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what my personal challenge will be — but keep you posted, yeah?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I think I am extremely arrogant, and the worst practitioner of this. It&amp;rsquo;s no secret this blog has many design quirks, it features my writing style heavily, and is also just various narrations of my personal life. So maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just reflecting. I still need to think more about this issue, I feel.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/on-leisure-spontaneity-and-why-id-like-to-receive-more-substacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/on-leisure-spontaneity-and-why-id-like-to-receive-more-substacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I took my first ever college midterm today, meaning I&amp;rsquo;m halfway through the semester; meaning I&amp;rsquo;m a quarter way through my first year; meaning I&amp;rsquo;m 1/16th done with college. For those of you asking how it&amp;rsquo;s going:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I often find myself thinking, more than anything else, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;so this is it?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From an etic perspective, I think I&amp;rsquo;m doing well in college. I say hi to lots of different people, some people say hi back; I eat relatively healthy; I sleep enough; I attend office hours; I&amp;rsquo;m doing well in my classes, which are largely small and generally interesting. I keep in touch with old friends, call my parents at regular intervals, walk often, look at morning sunlight, drink enough water, and keep up a supplement regime. I work out five times a week, I run at a slightly lesser frequency. I&amp;rsquo;ve largely avoided the weed-outs, the gen-eds, and the freshman traps. I joined clubs I was interested in, all of which are novel activities. I practice my languages consistently and hang out with Chinese people occasionally. My room is clean, comfortable, and decorated. I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what I want to study, but I like not knowing. I don&amp;rsquo;t procrastinate as badly as I did in high school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/rocky-mount--the-rocky-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/rocky-mount--the-rocky-mountains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I packed up my college life in a few hours — a task that the single word &amp;ldquo;pack&amp;rdquo; compresses to seem manageable; the actual process of compression in reality being absolutely not manageable — and set off to Banff. I skip over some of the emotions around this time, ones similar in vein to [[goodbye to farewell]] — but it&amp;rsquo;s also cheating to refer you to earlier emotions I once had, and so please fill in the blanks however you expect the end of my first year to have felt, as is your right in my failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Date: 2025-05-26&#xA;Pages: 364&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/sf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/sf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At a scholarship &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; weekend, I anticipated the most boring event would be the small-group panel with two alums. I say this because the alums in my room were, to me at the time, fairly cookie cutter — successful, upper-middle class millennials. Our earlier guest speaker was a Rhodes Scholar/former aspiring astronaut/Silk Road biker, for context.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The event went basically as I expected. The boxed lunch was also not very good. The speakers were kind, offered good insight into college, and really likeable. To me at the time, though, I assumed there was no way these people were &amp;ldquo;considered&amp;rdquo; — how could someone &lt;em&gt;seriously&lt;/em&gt; reflect and question and still end up in a similar, conventional place? — and so, as an iconoclastic, angsty, existentially confused high school senior, I felt somewhat turned off by the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/slow-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/slow-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I once spent a summer at home trying to get out of the house as much as possible. Conversation after conversation later, the mundane began to wear. No one was fast, I thought to myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And so, for a little while, I prided myself on speed in the literal sense. I&amp;rsquo;d predict where conversations were going and head them off. You watch a few patterns, here and there, and it sometimes didn&amp;rsquo;t even matter if the other person was going to say the thing that you said for them, because people beforehand had completed the sentence the same way. The curse, of course, being that each conversation began to bleed further and further. Contexts were merged; stories were conflated. Fast became more about speed than style, and rewards were found in quantity than quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/spring-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/spring-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tel aviv, the west bank, and an argument to lightly hold your beliefs. last updated 05/06/2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-disclaimers-and-the-structure-of-this-post&#34;&gt;some disclaimers and the structure of this post&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post was written as my final project for a course on Israel and Palestine (outlined in [[#background]]). I first recap the course to explain the context for the trip that the class took to Israel and Palestine, then make a general argument for the advantages of lightly holding one&amp;rsquo;s beliefs — even the deepest held ones — informed by, and analysed through the lens of, what I saw on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/swore-id-seen-you-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/swore-id-seen-you-before/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;or, march&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I always thought February had 24 days. Not usually a big deal; quite relevant when planning travel. An extra week in Chiang Mai won&amp;rsquo;t kill me, but it does have some visa implications I need to sort — something I&amp;rsquo;m putting off by writing this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-observations&#34;&gt;some observations&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the little changes are sometimes all you need: lattes to espressos, drake to novo amor, a little laugh once in a while;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;backlit anything, concrete, wood, plants in some combination;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;vibes, energy, and the human experience are equally legit to authority;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the meditation retreat probably — probably — changed my life;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;scheduling that flows feels better than what life is now — a lot of dead time (perhaps this is a benefit of advance planning);&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;coffee, tea, wine, fine dining, menswear, cigars, running shoes, watches, brandy, whisky, cologne, when did the beautifully complication of every niche begin, why do these little communities always exist?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-changes&#34;&gt;some changes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;i never thought i&amp;rsquo;d buy a barbour jacket, i now own one;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;aesthetic continues to consume;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;is solitude a blessing? a life skill? a harmful habit?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;integrity, pro-social is definitely confirmed — sometimes selfish, sometimes not, but definitely confirmed;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bryan Johnson;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;words have fallen a bit out of fashion — attribute it to sleep, meditation, lack of suitability, Thailand&amp;rsquo;s culinary scene, who knows;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;varia&#34;&gt;varia&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the thai teen who wanted to listen to kendrick lamar;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the amount of French presence;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;hostel &amp;amp; backpacker culture continues to be a bit too hot; this life of solitude continues to be a bit too cold; Bangkok was probably the right amount but hard to replicate;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ah, hello, April&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was once in a car when I asked &amp;ldquo;how would you guys define clean to someone with no life experience&amp;rdquo;; to which someone responded &amp;ldquo;not dirty&amp;rdquo;; at which point I launched the argument &amp;ldquo;well what is dirty?&amp;rdquo;; silence &amp;amp; then &amp;ldquo;you need to get back to school&amp;rdquo; responded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How does one define irresponsibility? Silliness? The line between the two? What is unhinged?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog, probably. This (section of the) blog probably lacks a certain level of grounding needed for lucidity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/twentyfive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/twentyfive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May 16th, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have no substantial memories from when I was ten. This cannot be literally true — I&amp;rsquo;m sure I remember &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; significant from when I was ten, but this memory is attached to another anchoring fact, like grade four or where we lived at the time or anything similar. The only memory I do have is that once, my mother and I were at a counter at some athletic club or something of that idea, and the clerk asked my age, and I dutifully stated &amp;ldquo;nine and three-quarters&amp;rdquo; while my mom answered &amp;ldquo;ten&amp;rdquo; at the same time. Then the clerk had me write my age down (unfortunately requiring the suppression of the important 3/4 qualifier). Later in the car, I curiously corrected my mother: &amp;ldquo;Mom, why do you round up? I&amp;rsquo;m so far from ten!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/vice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/vice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;drink&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;gin &amp;amp; tonic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;vodka soda&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;this one Japanese sugar-filled monstrosity that costs about a dollar and is only 3%&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;soju&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;cigar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;this one davidoff tasting cigar that a salesperson kindly gave me in Zurich&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;romeo y julieta no.2&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;davidoff churchill&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;house blend @# Real Hermanos @ TTDI, Malaysia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the ones Lucas Schmidt brought to the grad party&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;wine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;~ (less so)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;song&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;coffee&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;peaberry espresso in Dar — strong then dissipates super quick. no real hints of anything&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;peaberry espresso at Akha Ahma — doesn&amp;rsquo;t dissipate in the same way&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;chiang mai catimor at Roast8ry — outrageously good. the first time i&amp;rsquo;ve picked up the hints of something at the end of the espresso. sweet. dissipates even BETTER than peaberry. merlot note lasts the longest, sweetness of the fruit nearer to the end of the espresso.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/wake-up-its-the-first-of-the-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/wake-up-its-the-first-of-the-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;or, february&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-observations&#34;&gt;some observations&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;i rarely think i have things to write about, until i read what those i admire have written;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the dying legs of a stage of life (think end of school year, end of a trip) kill a lot of motivation;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;use of emojis (writ large, realistically) but especially in a semi-professional setting isn&amp;rsquo;t for me. i get it, but i can&amp;rsquo;t do it;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;capitalisation is good when writing, i&amp;rsquo;ll give myself some leeway on listicle content;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;awareness &amp;amp; effort play a larger role in the value of something than i thought, and perhaps commitment is okay after all;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;and so it goes&amp;rdquo; has become a preferred term when writing, sorry for stealing it from Kurt Vonnegut;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-changes&#34;&gt;some changes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;integrity, pro-social has revealed its importance to me, looks like the zoom wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that needed;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;forced reflection is underrated;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;should probably fix my posture;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;exercise is missed deeply;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;external image became consuming for a bit;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;small purchases/actions in line with the person — stupid? not viscerally obvious so far;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-miscellany&#34;&gt;some miscellany&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;only children and alone time (cred: Anjali);&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;segmenting home rest, physical rest, and the mental guard (cred: Kiki);&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;dumb off time, smart on time, and the circle (cred: Harsehaj);&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;perhaps paying more than your share isn&amp;rsquo;t such a bad thing;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/west32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://randyxchang.github.io/randall/posts/west32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;just a couple of new kids on the block&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks in Cleveland have gone by. &lt;em&gt;Does your body want to chew glass&lt;/em&gt;, Benedict H. wrote. Aurelius confessed pages of gold, that said similar things, that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand as much.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This weekend, we went (to my) home. Mom asked what had happened in the last few weeks. I told her about this 2007 movie, &lt;em&gt;West 32nd&lt;/em&gt;, starring John Cho, and how I went through every method, in vain, trying to find a copy of it. Every streaming service, every pirating website, every torrent forum. In the end, I bought a DVD secondhand (Amazon said all four of my potential addresses were out of shipping radius) off eBay. Subtracting five seconds to eat another bite of our favourite pizza, my mom found a working file on some Chinese website in twenty seconds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
